Guide to the Janina Wojcicki Hoskins Papers, 1949-1994
Department of Special Collections
Janina Wojcicki Hoskins Papers,
1949-1994
Special Collections M0820
Hoskins, Janina Wojcicki.
11 linear ft.
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
None.
Provenance
Gift of Prof. and Mrs. Stanley Wojcicki, 1995.
Biography
Polish emigre who escaped the Communist regime in 1949, first to Sweden, later moving to the United States where she became the Slavic bibliographer at the Library of Congress
Scope and Content
Personal and professional correspondence, reference files and written drafts of various articles and books dealing particularly with Thaddeus Kosciuszko, I. J. Paderewski, the memoirs of Krystyna Narbutt, music collections in Poland, Polish printing and rare books, Polish manuscripts in the Library of Congress, the visual arts in Poland, and personal memoirs including information about Stanislaw Mikolajczyk.
Access Terms
Henry III, King of Poland.; Jefferson, Thomas, 1743-1826.; Kosciuszko, Thaddeus.; Kowalski, William.; Lewanski, Richard Casimir, 1918-; Lelewel, Joachin.; Mikolajczyk, Stanislaw.; Narbutt, Krystyna.; Paderewski, Ignace Jan, 1860-1941.; Sudnik, George.; Wetter, Maija.; Bibliography.; Slavic literature.; Poland--History--1945-1980.
Container List
- Biographical file (Box 1)
- Krystyna Narbutt. Memoirs from a stay in America, n.d. (Box 1)
- Library of Congress, Reference Dept. Annual reports, 1972-1989 (Box 1)
- William Kowalski. George Sudnik, artist, 1993 (Box 1)
- Correspondence: professional, personal, dealers, and reference. (Box 1)
  Includes National Library of Poland and the Kosciuszko Foundation
- Offprints, 1980s (Box 1)
- Library of Congress performance appraisals, 1980s (Box 1)
- Bibliography of Thaddeus Kosciuszko, n.d. (Box 1)
- Embassy of the U.S. in Poland file (Box 1)
- Correspondence with Richard C. Lewanski, 1970s (Box 1)
- Alliance College Library (Box 1)
- Typescripts by others (Box 2)
- Photographs (Box 2)
- Publishing in Poland: typescript by J.W.H., 1955 (Box 2)
- Annotated bibliography on Polish Fine Art, by J.W.H., n.d. (Box 2)
- Memoirs of Krystyna Narbutt, n.d. (Box 2)
- Henry III, King of Poland, reference material (Box 2)
- correspondence carbons, 1981-1983 (Box 2)
- Reports of trips to Poland, 1976 & 1978 (Box 3)
- Music collections in Poland (Box 3)
- Manuscripts relating to Poland and Polish holdings in Library of Congress (Box 3)
- Thomas Jefferson views of Poland, JWH, 1976 (Box 3)
- Reference files on Kosciuszko (Box 3)
- Professional correspondence (Box 3)
- Bibliography on Poland, general (Box 3)
- 500 years of printing in Polant (Box 3)
- Significant rare books relating to Poland and the Polish Nation, JWH, ca. 1966 (Box 3)
- Reference files (Box 3)
- Important biographical information including letter about escape from Poland from Stanislaw Mikolajczyk, 11 April 1949. (Box 4)
- Legal papers giving power of attorney to lawyer in Poland to defend husband, 1951-1959 (Box 4)
- Autobiographical typescript, n.d. (Box 4)
- Materials for exhibits at Library of Congress (Box 4)
- Clippings about JWH (Box 4)
- Photos (Box 4)
- Library of Congress personal biographical file (Box 4)
- Correspondence, carbon copies, 1980s (Box 4)
- Reference files re Kosciuszko (Box 4)
- Correspondence (Box 4)
- Expense records (Box 4)
- Library of Congress Bulletins (Box 5)
- Retirement award, photos (Box 5)
- Library of Congress exhibit files (Box 5)
- Proof of "Visual arts in Poland" (Box 5)
- Maija Wetter watercolors (Box 5)
- 3 unidentified audio tapes; 1 unidentified roll microfilm (Box 5)
- Professional slides from Polish National Library (Box 5)
- More important personal documents, 1949-1951, & 1956 (Box 6)
- "From the past," by JWH (Box 6)
- Documents about the Thomas Jefferson bust (Box 6)
- Audio tape: I.J. Paderewski's "Speech to America" (Polish), 1940 (Box 6)
- Correspondence from friend in NY when JWH was in Sweden, 1949 (Box 6)
  [Helen Banczyk?]
- Important letters, 1949-1952 (Box 6)
- 2 unidentified audio tapes, 1 microfilm (Box 6)
- Exhibit material on Joachin Lelewel (Box 6)
- photocopies (Box 7)
- memos from Library of Congress (Box 7)
- clippings (Box 7)
- reference materials (and published book), "Visual Arts in Poland," 1993 (Box 7)